Finding Aid for the Philip Edward Chandler Papers LSC.0270
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Landscape Design / Horticulture
  - Plant Lists by Philip Chandler
    - California natives for landscape use. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Effective plant combinations for shaded areas (thin shade, strong light). (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Evergreen screening materials for containers on windy balconies or decks. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Foliage predominantly red-green, bronze and copper. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Gray-green sequence in plant materials. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lawn trees. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Linear and needle-leaved plants. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Linear-leaved sequence by Schinus molle (One doesn't need all of them!). (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Little plants for little places. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Perennials useful in Southern California. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Plant materials for fragrance (Southern California). (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Plants for full shade. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Plant materials useful in containers. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Plant materials for seashore (Southern California). (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Plants for the tropical look in Southern California (Palms & edible fruits listed separately). (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Principal palms in California. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Remarkable trees of greater Los Angeles. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Rock garden plants and sources--Chris Rosmini and Bob Smaus. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Significant ground covers for greater Los Angeles. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Silver foliage for the Southern California landscape. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Trees we should know (in greater Los Angeles). (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Tropical and sub-tropical fruits in Southern California. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - When they flower in Los Angeles. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Yellow--green foliage. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Research Materials
    - Tree specimens, garden details--photos (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Evans & Reeves nurseries plant list--With annotations by PC., (?)., 1950s (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Herbs--unidentified published list, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - List of herbs--Taylor's Garden, San Gabriel, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Plant journals, publications, handbooks, v.d. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Streatfield, David. Rancho Los Alamitos Garden Restoration--historical narrative, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Teaching
    - Class Intineraries, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Home Landscape (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Horticultural exam, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Ornamental Horticulture and Garden Design (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Plant Combination Theory, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Plant Materials in Landscaping for Professionals: Tropical effects ... (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Plant Materials in Landscaping for Professionals: Interior Planting ... (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Random notes for workshop handout (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Small plants for small places--Slide lecture(?). With list of slides, notes, photos. See also Box 6, folder 7, slide pp.52-53, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tributes from students, 1972-1973. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Plant Matter and Plant Composition--UCLA extension course Art S193F, 1974-1976. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Theory of Plant Combination in Planting Design--UCLA lecture, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Handouts--design notebook by Paula Dietz, New York Times, August 28, 1980. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Personal
  - Correspondence
    - Christmas cards, 1978, 1988, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Letters from Dick Chapman, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Garden Tours
    - Itineraries, 1985, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - General
    - Photographs. (Box 7)
  - General [Slides]
    - Miscellaneous--pp.9(#12)-14(#1), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified house interior--p. 18(#9-14), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Odds & ends--p. 42(#13)-47 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - p. 48(#16-19), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous--p. 56(#8-20), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Odds & ends--p. 48(#1-9) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Snapshots and portraits, mostly unidentified. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Sketches of garden details [copies], poem (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Portraits
    - Philip Chandler--photographs, (?)., 1937-1990 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Symposiums Attended
    - Santa Barbara Botanic Gardens--landscape design, 1989. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Santa Barbara Botanic Garden--Mediterranean plants, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Travel
    - Scotland--pp.24(#1)-24(#2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - San Francisco, 1976--pp.48(#20)-49(#17) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Various states, countries--photographs. (Box 7)
    - Various states, countries--postcards. (Box 8)
  - Travel [Slides]
    - Hawaii--pp.1-3, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hawaii--pp.4-6, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hawaii--pp.7-8 (#12), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Japan--p. 14(#2)-14(#16), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Mt. Desert, N.E. Harbor, Maine--p. 26(#10-20), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Martha's Vineyard--pp.25(#16)-26(#9), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Europe--pp.24(#3)-25(#12), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - England--pp.22(#2)-23(#20) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Europe--p. 17(#1-17), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Europe--pp.14(#17)-16(#20), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Northern Ireland--p. 25(#13-15) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mt. Desert, N.E. Harbor, Maine--p. 27 (#8), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Mexico--pp.27(#9)-29(#3), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - England--pp.31(#8)-35(#4) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hawaii--p. 35(#1-5), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hawaii--pp.36(#1)-42(#12), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Rancho Santa Fe, --pp.49(#18)-50(#6), July 19, 1978 1978. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Powderhorn Ranch--p. 57 (#1-11), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Southern California History
  - Notes by Bob Armacost
    - Clippings re Santa Monica, Westgate, Sawtelle, Westwood--Clippings and holograph note by Bob Armacost. Folders 24-28 from Bob Armacost, 1980-1989. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Orchid growing at Armacost & Royston by Robert L. Armacost, September 1983. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - A brief history of Armacost and Royston by Robert L. Armacost, January 1981. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Early memories of Santa Monica and Sawtelle by Robert L. Armacost--With appendix dated July 1989 and letter to PC dated October 20, 1990, 1989-1990. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Letters and notes to Philip Chandler from Bob Armacost, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Writings by Others
  - George H. Spalding by Mildred Mathias, n.d.; 3 pp. Rough draft. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Writings by Philip Chandler
  - Santa Barbara Safari--Alternate title: Spring in Santa Barbara, n.d.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ornamental Plants for California Gardens, n.d.; ca. 210 pp. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ornamental Plants for California Gardens, n.d.; ca. 225 pp. Offset print with holograph notes. (Box 4, Folder 3)